<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Best_Practices_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Best_Practices_Guide-Networking" lang="en-US">
	<title>Networking</title>
	 <para>
		Networking is as important a component to your cloud as other hardware and software. Without a good, redundant, high bandwidth network your cloud could have problems including long transfer times, virtual machine failures, and loss of data.
	</para>
	 <para>
		Generally speaking, ten-gigabit networking is generally recommended for storage access when larger servers that can support relatively more VMs are used.
	</para>
	 <section id="sect-Best_Practices_Guide-Networking-IP_Address_Planning">
		<title>IP Address Planning</title>
		 <para>
			The administrator should provide 
			<indexterm>
				<primary>private IP addresses</primary>
			</indexterm>
			 for the system in each pod and provision them in CloudStack.
		</para>

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-Best_Practices_Guide-Networking-NIC_Bonding">
		<title>NIC Bonding</title>
		 <para>
			Network Interface Card, or NIC, 
			<indexterm>
				<primary>bonding</primary>
			</indexterm>
			 is important to maintaining connectivity throughout your cloud when network problems loom. When done properly, 
			<indexterm>
				<primary>NIC bonding</primary>
			</indexterm>
			 provides a redundant path for data to flow in the event that one network fails. Because bonding is generally managed through the hypervisor, the procedure for creating bonds can differ depending on the software being used. Common among all hypervisors, however, is the requirement of network interfaces to be addressed identically on all hosts.
		</para>

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-Best_Practices_Guide-Networking-vSphere">
		<title>Networking in vSphere</title>
		 <para>
			For vSphere with advanced virtual networking, we recommend provisioning enough private IPs for your total number of customers, plus enough for the required CloudStack System VMs. Typically, about 10 additional IPs are required for the System VMs. For more information about System VMs, see Working with System Virtual Machines in the Administrator's Guide.
		</para>
		 <para>
			The Management Servers communicate with VMware vCenter servers on port 443 (HTTPs).
		</para>

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-Best_Practices_Guide-Networking-KVM_and_XenServer">
		<title>Networking in KVM and XenServer</title>
		 <para>
			For KVM and XenServer, the recommended number of private IPs per Pod is one per host. If you expect a Pod to grow, add enough private IPs now to accommodate the growth.
		</para>
		 <para>
			When Advanced Virtual networking is being used, the number of private IP addresses available in each Pod varies depending on which hypervisor is running on the nodes in that Pod. Citrix XenServer and KVM use link-local addresses, which in theory provide more than 65,000 private IP addresses within the address block. As the Pod grows over time, this should be more than enough for any reasonable number of hosts as well as IP addresses for guest virtual routers. VMWare ESXi, by contrast uses any administrator-specified subnetting scheme, and the typical administrator provides only 255 IPs per Pod. Since these are shared by physical machines, the guest virtual router, and other entities, it is possible to run out of private IPs when scaling up a Pod whose nodes are running ESXi.
		</para>
		 <para>
			To ensure adequate headroom to scale private IP space in an ESXi Pod when Advanced Virtual networking is enabled, use one or more of the following techniques:
		</para>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Specify a larger CIDR block for the subnet. A subnet mask with a /20 suffix will provide more than 4,000 IP addresses.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Create multiple pods, each with its own subnet. For example, if you create 10 Pods and each pod has 255 IPs, this will provide 2,550 IP addresses.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The secondary storage VMs and console proxy VMs connect to the Management Server on port 8250. If you are using multiple Management Servers, the load balanced IP address of the Management Servers on port 8250 must be reachable. Note that you must not expose port 8250 to the public Internet. The secondary storage VM can be located on any Host in the Zone. It uses the private network for its communication.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The Management Server and secondary storage VMs must be able to access vCenter and all ESXi hosts in the zone. To allow the necessary access through the firewall, keep port 443 open.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The console proxy VMs connect to all hosts in the Zone over the private network. Therefore the private network of any given Pod in the Zone must have connectivity to the private network of all other Pods in the Zone.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The secondary storage NFS export is mounted by the secondary storage VM. Secondary storage traffic goes over the private network even if there is a separate storage network. (Primary storage traffic goes over the storage network, if available.) If you choose to place secondary storage NFS servers on the storage network, you must make sure there is a route from the private network to the storage network.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					When external firewall integration is in place, the public IP VLAN must still be trunked to the Hosts. This is required to support the Secondary Storage and Console Proxy VMs.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The Management Servers communicate with each other to coordinate tasks amongst themselves. This communication uses TCP on ports 8250 and 9090.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					With Advanced Networking, separate subnets must be used for private and public networks.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The public internet must not be able to access port 8096 on the Management Server.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The Management Servers communicate with the XenServers on ports 22 (ssh) and 80 (HTTP).
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The Management Servers communicate with the KVM servers on port 22 (ssh).
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>

	</section>
	

</chapter>

