<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Best_Practices_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Best_Practices_Guide-Clusters">
	<title>Clusters</title>
	<para>
		In cloud organization, Clusters are the smallest organizational unit.  Hosts, running a common hypervisor, join together to form a cluster and receive virtual machines.
	</para>
	<section id="sect-Best_Practices_Guide-Clusters-Limits">
		<title>Recommended Limits</title>
		<para>
			In order to maintain an efficient cloud, Citrix recommends the following logical limits when building your cloud:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>A maximum of six hosts per cluster.  You can have an unlimited number of clusters per pod and the number of storage pools per cluster does not matter.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>No more than 200 virtual disks per LUN.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Each hypervisor supports a maximum number of virtual machines per host.  It is important to follow the manufacturer's recommendations.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>There are no practical limits on SRs per cluster.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para><indexterm><primary>maintenance</primary><secondary>host downtime</secondary></indexterm>It is also important to take into consideration host downtime.  To maintain uptime whenever possible your cloud should be designed to have a host go down and have all VMs on that host migrate over to other hosts without violating the above recommendations.</para>
	</section>	
	<section id="sect-Best_Practices_Guide-Clusters-Switch_Density">
		<title>Network Switch Density</title>
		<para>
			<indexterm><primary>networking</primary><secondary>switch density</secondary></indexterm>Multiple clusters can be used per pod to achieve a certain switch density.  In advance networking, too many VLANs can be problematic.  To reduce the number of VLANs a cluster has to handle customers should be assigned to a particular cluster and not be scattered throughout the cloud.  This can be accomplished by setting the value <command>use.user.concentrated.pod.allocation</command> to <command>true</command>.
		</para>
	</section>

</chapter>

