<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Best_Practices_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Best_Practices_Guide-Building_your_cloud">
	<title>Building Your Cloud</title>
	<para>
		So you are ready to start building your cloud using the CloudStack management software.  Here are a few tips and tricks to help you be successful in your rollout.
	</para>
	<section id="sect-Best_Practices_Guide-Building_your_cloud-Staging_Area">
		<title>Staging Area</title>
		<para>
			Having a <indexterm><primary>staging system</primary></indexterm><indexterm><primary>testing updates</primary></indexterm>staging system that models your production environment is strongly advised.  It is critical if customizations have been applied to your CloudStack environment.  A staging system allows you to make changes to your system so you can determine if there are any negative effects.  Upgrades and patches all change your system's behavior.  All changes should be tested before making changes to your production environment.  Your staging system should be as identical to your production system as well.  Small differences in hardware can be problematic when testing upgrades and patches.  What affects one system may not affect the other.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="sect-Best_Practices_Guide-Building_your_cloud-Time">
		<title>Taking adequate time for planning.</title>
		<para>
			<indexterm><primary>planning</primary></indexterm>When assembling your cloud, you should allow adequate time for installation, a beta, and learning the system and software.  Installs with Basic Networking can be done in a day or two.  Installs with Advanced Networking usually take several days for the first attempt, with complicated installations taking longer.  Allow at least 4-8 weeks for a beta to work through all of the integration issues.  It can takes months to gain confidence using cloud-technologies and CloudStack.
		</para>
	</section>

</chapter>

